in this video I'm going to show you how
you can set up tricentis Tosca 16.0 and
run it on a AWS ec2 Windows Server
instance
now there are very simple steps to do
this first we need to set up a ec2
Windows server on AWS and then we need
to download the tricentis Tosca latest
version and then install it on that
Windows server
and then simply we need to connect to
our Cloud license server for Tosca and
start running Tosca commander on a
Windows ec2 server
so let's get started
the first step is to create a Windows
ec2 server on AWS now to do that you
need to have a account on AWS I would be
using a free tire account
which means I have got some limited
bandwidth and time on which I can run a
free Windows ec2 server but you can have
your own choice of servers and uh your
own configuration you don't need to
follow the configuration which I am
going to currently run on
so let's get started I'm already logged
in with my AWS ec2 account and you can
either go to services and search for ec2
which is the virtual servers in the
cloud
so click on that and that should take
you to the ec2 dashboard now it should
show you all the instances which are
currently running on your ec2
if not it will show zero instances are
running
so I need to run uh instance a Windows
instance on this ec2 so I'm going to
click on launch launch instance
and here I need to fill some details
before I can start running a Windows ec2
server
so let's get started with the name so
I'm going to name it Tosca web server
and then I need to select a application
or a Amazon machine image which is also
known as Ami now as you can see there
are lots of different images here that
is Mac OS that is Linux Ubuntu
and others right but we need a Windows
server and hence I would uh select a
Windows image Now by default it will
select me a free tag eligible uh base
image which is the Windows Server 2022
that's exactly what I need if you uh
want to have a more powerful or a
different image which uh you want to
select then you are
free to select any of the images but by
default it will select you the best
possible image
okay coming down uh coming to instance
type right now again
my instance is a free tire eligible
instance right but if you want to select
a different instance type I would
recommend you to go for a higher memory
instance which means either go for a T2
large which is 8 gigabytes memory or
even more but if you want to run Tosca
continuously on This Server I would
recommend to go with the t2 large which
has got a 8GB memory and that should be
enough to run Tosca on this Windows
server but for me uh for this particular
video I would stick to the t2 micro
which has got 1GB memory it's not enough
but for my purpose it is fine
now coming to a key pair if uh you have
a key pair already created you can go
ahead and select that I've already won
but for this particular video I would
create a new key pair
so let's name it Tosca server
okay and the private key file format
should be dot pm I would tell you why we
require.pm it would be required while we
try to get the password for the Windows
server but for now just keep it dot PM
okay and create the key pair it should
download it automatically
now coming to network settings okay
um either I can create a new security
group or a select existing Security
Group let's create a new one so that uh
we are well aware of what is required so
we require the RDP traffic
let's keep it uh anywhere you can always
change it to my IP so that it always
allows only through your IP the RDP
connection
um you need uh either HTTP or https but
I generally keep it both okay so we need
these three settings
um or these three security groups at
least
um in your network settings without this
um your
or your web server will not work okay
now coming to storage
that is 30 gigabytes which is enough to
run a Tosca
commander on the web server so I would
leave it
and then there are Advanced details
which we don't need to care about these
are if you want to have some specific
behavior for your web server but these
are not uh something which we need to
change so these are the mandatory
settings and the important ones which I
have to change okay
um once this is done um I can also
decide on a number of instances for now
it is one but if you want to run Tosca
server and Tosca commander on different
instances you can even launch two
instances okay
so click on launch instance
and that should quickly uh create your
instance and start running it go to view
all instances to view your instance that
should
um change the instance state in a few
minutes and start running it okay once
it starts running then we can even
connect to that instance
okay so let's wait until this uh
instance starts running
and we would require the dot PM later on
while we connect to this instance
okay as you can see the instance date
has now changed to running so let's
select this instance you can see all the
details here for this instance and the
security which we have created the
networking the storage
monitoring tags everything would be
available here okay
including the IP address which should be
required to connect to your
server but probably it's not required
um there is a direct way to connect to
it okay
so now select that instance and click on
connect
now in connect to instance there are
three options but we will stick to the
RDP client which is the more simpler one
and probably
it is the most easiest one now ignore
this message if you are getting this
um it doesn't matter
the connection type it will be
automatically selected Connect using RDP
client you need to click on download
remote desktop file that's the RDP file
through which we'll be connecting so
click on that to download it
and we have the DNS username
administrator right the only thing which
we require is the password
okay
now
I can click on this to start the RDP
connection
but I still require the password as you
can see right now there is a way to get
password here if you can see uh get
password click on that and that should
open a get Windows password
um section and here you have got the
instance ID and here we need to upload
the private key file which we just
created
while generating our key pair right and
that's the dot PM format
so click on upload and select the dot PM
file which we created earlier
click on open and that should upload
that PM file here
and then we just need to click on
decrypt password
so once you do that you should get the
password here I will just copy it
and then let's go back to our RDP here
and we'll paste it here
we should just go through this dialogs
to get the connection working
and now we are connecting to our AWS ec2
Windows server
so once the connection is established
you will see the Windows Server starting
it will ask you to select a network
which will connect to your local network
so click on yes
um on that Network dialog box
uh it will change the theme by running
uh something in the background so you
will get this theme for your Windows
server
and
that completes our first step so we have
successfully set up a Windows ec2 server
on AWS and it is in running condition
and we have also connected to that
server
so the next step is to get our Tosca
version installed on this particular
Windows Server right so for that we need
to go to the tracentes portal so let's
open
uh Microsoft Edge and from there I will
go to the tricentes portal
so just go through this setup of which
shows up every time you set up Windows
Edge for the first time
so just go through that whole setup and
then
um you should get started with the edge
browser
once that is done let's open up the
tricentes support portal where we would
get our
Tosca installer
so I would search for try centers
support that should take me to the
transientist support website
and we need to login into the support
website
now before we move forward
um obviously you need to have a valid
transcendus support account
where you have created that account and
you have already requested a license
now if you don't know how to do that
watch the other video where I've shown
you how you can request a training
license for your where I have shown you
how you can request a toscal training
license
so click on login and
here just use the same email and
password which you have created an
account with
so I will use my email
and my password
and just click on login that should take
you inside the dress and test support
website
now once you log in we need to go to the
tri-centers license request page right
so the URL is this
um
it is available in the video description
if you require it but this we have
already done it so you should know this
so just
copy paste this URL and click on it so
that we land on this particular page
where we have already a cloud training
license which is deployed and there is
also a link to download press and
testoster
so click on that and here we'll try to
find our Tosca version which is 16.0 the
latest right now here in the downloads
page you will see there are lots of
different uh products from tracentes but
we are only interested in class and
testoster so click on that
here you will find lots of different
Oscar versions but we need to find the
Tosca 16.0 LTS right don't get confused
uh with the different products there are
different products related to 16.0 but
look for uh Tosca in the product and
title should be Transcendence Tosca 16.0
LTS
um and the version should be 16.0 so
this is the Tosca installer which we
need to download okay so click on that
and that should start your download for
your Tosca version
now
um it's around 1.5 GB so it will take a
few minutes to download and once it's
downloaded then uh we'll start off with
uh installing this Tosca version on this
Windows server
so now that the download is complete
let's go ahead and go to this folder it
is in the zip format so we need to first
uh
extract this folder so let's do that
so that we get the actual installer
once that's completed you will get two
files uh one is the application and one
is the sha256 file but uh you need to
click on this uh application which is
um the actual installer so double click
on it to start the Tosca installer
once the installer has started you will
get this kind of a window with a welcome
message you need to click on I agree to
license terms and continue
you just need to follow everything which
is displayed on this window and you
should be installed uh pretty easy this
Tosca setup okay so all these
prerequisite if these are not installed
trash and this setup would install it
for you so just click on next
um choose the setup that best suits or
needs we can set up this machine as an
execution agent we can set up a custom
installation but we need to install
Tosca Commander so we'll keep it as it
is click on next
all these are the default folders for
Tosca so I don't need to change them
click on next
um this is Tosca Diagnostics if you want
you can keep it or remove it
this is the update service if you want
to enable the update service by default
or else just click on next uh something
related to Tosca data Integrity I don't
need to install it
this is related to Vision AI engine I
believe it as it is it will install the
vision AI engine for me
and then it will show you a summary of
what it is going to install okay so you
can still change features which you
don't need and remove them but um I
would say just stick to the default and
go through the installation
so now it will install all the different
uh setups it may take some time
depending on your machine configuration
once the installation is completed you
should get a summary with all the text
on all the different components you can
even look at the logs if something goes
wrong
now just to finish the installation we
need to click on finish
and that should complete our next steps
to download and install Tosca 16.0 on
your Windows server
now if you go to a Windows menu you
should see a Transcendence folder with
all the different types in this
components which are installed on this
Windows machine or server
out of this the most interesting is the
Tosca Commander or the most important I
would say so click on that to launch our
Tosca Commander now and we are only left
with the final step uh it is to connect
to our cloud training license server so
that our Tosca Commander can use that
license and we can launch out of
commander on this Windows server
now since we have not activated any
license it will take you to this license
page where you need to enter a username
and password to connect to your cloud
training license now if you are on
different uh license model don't worry
uh just go back to manage and then also
go to activate and click on connect that
should give you different options like a
self-hosted license server if you want
to install it directly on the server or
use licenses from my local machine right
but I am going to connect to the cloud
hosted license server because that's
what I have used okay so I need to use
the same username and password which
I've created an account on the
transientist support portal right so
let's go ahead and use that same
username and password
which we used earlier
and click on OK
bank that worked like a charm right so
now we have connected to the license
server and we can start using Commander
Tosca Commander right away okay
um it will take you to this page once it
has connected to the license server uh
here you can create your own project so
let's go ahead and do that uh so here
you can create your new workspace as you
know there are different types of
workspaces if we have also got a
database we can create a multi-user
workspace for now I will stick to the
single user workspace I will leave the
location as it is and I will
select the name for the new workspace I
would also
use the standard workspace template
which is the standard TSU
and click on OK
so it will start creating my new single
user workspace
and now it will start launching the
project or which we have created now
so it will open all the different
modules or the different sections which
are present in Tosca Commander and you
can see test cases modules requirements
test design execution
Etc right so everything is present here
um the only last thing which is also
important
so while scanning any module so right
now if I if I'm going to scan a
particular module so let me open Chrome
for that matter now by default you will
not get Google Chrome in your Windows
Server when you launch a new AWS ec2 but
in the background I did download and
install Google Chrome
so let's just open google.com and try to
scan some modules with our new Tosca
so let's go back to Tosca and create a
new module and try to scan the speech so
right click and
create a new folder here
let's call it Google for now
and now let's right click on this and
try to scan this application
and now you you should notice that you
are not able to scan that particular
application because it's open in Chrome
and every browser requires an extension
uh before you can
scan your objects in that browser using
Tosca so you need to install a Tosca
extension and that is the last thing
which I wanted to show you
so uh once it starts this x-scan it is
going to realize that that extension is
not installed on this browser
so let's try and select Google Chrome
here and try to scan
and as you can see now it is throwing a
message saying browser extension not
installed or outdated right so
in order to scan you need to install
this extension from Tosca and let's
click on yes so it will directly take us
to that page where we can install this
extension
and then here we just need to add this
extension to our Chrome browser
so click on add to Chrome
and it should start adding this
extension
once that's done then our Tosca
installation would be complete and we
would be able to scan a module using
um Chrome browser
so that's completed we can close that
window and go back to our Google module
and let's try to scan again this time
around it should work
okay so the X scan is already running in
the background
so let's wait
okay so now you can see that message did
not appear and now I can go to the
advanced tab
and I can just uh maybe just add some
controls
okay so this item is not unique
um I can even change it
by image or by index
to make it unique
let's let's go with index
and that makes it unique okay so that's
all I wanted to do here uh I will click
on Save quickly uh to save this module
okay and then close this window
so now our scanning is also working we
can scan modules with the Chrome browser
so that completes the whole setup okay
so the whole setup consisted of
basically three steps the first step was
to create a Windows ec2 server on AWS
and then we installed we downloaded and
installed the Tosca 16.0 version on this
Windows ec2 server we connected to the
cloud license uh using our training
license which we deployed already
and then we finally installed the
extension on the Chrome browser and we
scanned few modules just to make sure
that everything is working as expected
so if you have noticed it's a little
slow uh because I am running on a very
low configuration Windows server
but ideally you should be running Tosca
on at least a 8 gigabit memory right so
just choose a higher version of ec2 uh
when you are creating a new Windows
Server if you want to run this for a
very long time right
um the only disadvantage is it would
incur some cost or charges on on your
AWS account but still it's a very good
option if you don't have that
configuration in your local machine or
you don't want to run Tosca on your
local machine you want to run it on a
virtual server so this way you can run
all your automation on a virtual server
and you can even start it from a Mac OS
right you cannot install uh Tosca on a
Mac machine but you can install it on a
Windows ec2 server and virtually start
it from the Mac OS right so you can
still run Tosca from a Mac OS or any
other OS using this way where you are
using using a AWS ec2 Windows server
so that's all for this video this is how
you can download and set up your Tosca
on a AWS ec2 server and start running
Tosca commander and start working on
your Tosca automation